# Barry Wang, PMP, Prince2, MSP, CSM, ITIL

## Senior Project Manager

Certified Senior Project Manager with over 10 years of experience in cloud/IT infrastructure, telecommunication & network, consulting and system integration, software development in small to large, complex environment. Managed multi-projects/products with sound business analysis skill and diverse technical background. Leader, mentor and team player interfacing with all levels of management and stakeholders.

Phone: +64273651442 Email: <u>barrywanghd@163.com</u> WebSite: <u>www.barry.wang</u>

#### **EXPERTISE**

- Strategic Planning and Management: Took program director role managing key programs from end to end perspective including creating statement of work, engaging key stakeholders, defining delivery strategy, controlling delivery according to baselines and afterward life cycle management. Helped account teams to achieve business targets in 5 extremely tough projects
- ➤ **Handling Multi Projects**: In charge of cloud infrastructure projects in BJS/PEK region and managing all CDN/DX infrastructure builds around APAC in AWS. Successfully managed over 18 projects/programs in Ericsson involving diverse solution areas and multi countries.
- ➤ **Team building/leadership:** Built up competence of charging, Voice over LTE and cloud for local key resources. Combined project goal and personal development of team members to reach win-win situation. Led the project team of 40+ members including subproject managers.
- ➤ **Continues improvement**: Innovatively introduced agile methodology to service delivery resulting in 10% efficiency improved regarding man effort involved. Kept coaching team's mind set of quality and used bottom-up approach turning around a vital project at risk.
- ➤ **Knowledge sharing**: Used SharePoint to manage projects, facilitate team collaboration, share information and knowledge. Created reused SharePoint web template for large scale projects. Presented project experience in Ericsson global seminars.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Project Management Methodologies, Agile, SDLC, Microsoft Project, Office Suite, SharePoint
- > Cloud, Telecommunication, Network, BSS,OSS, Media & Application, Programming, Web

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- > PMP Project Management Professional
- Prince2 (Practitioner) Projects in a Controlled Environment
- MSP (Practitioner) Managing Successful Programmes
- CSM Certified Scrum Master
- ITIL Foundation Certified Version 3
- Ericsson Certified Senior Project Manager for Consulting and System Integration.

Certificates & Awards scanned: <a href="http://www.barry.wang/Certificates.html">http://www.barry.wang/Certificates.html</a>
Project Management Reference Case: <a href="http://www.barry.wang/Project.html">http://www.barry.wang/Project.html</a>

Barry Wang Page 1 of 3

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

#### Technical Program Manager Amazon Web Service 2015 to Present

- > Develop and manage all infrastructure projects in BJS/PEK region to enhance infrastructure and its operations including new data centre design, construction, mechanical and electrical equipment, power and cooling, network deployment, existing site expansion and rework etc.
- ➤ Act as a bridge between infrastructure teams on the ground and business teams to ensure that stringent standards are met in the most cost-efficient way. Successfully handled all pull-in requests so far to meet high customer demands in BJS region.
- Manage CDN/DX infrastructure builds (new site, expansion, refresh, network scaling) around APAC as portfolio manager. Define delivery strategy, governance projects owned by different project managers around APAC, prioritize resources and escalate key issues to Seattle.
  - **Projects & Achievements:** BJS region expansion & New Site, PEK Site Exit & Migration.

#### Senior Project Manager Ericsson Region North East Asia 2007 to 2015

- > Started from access level project manager to senior level by delivering increasingly complex projects and passing certification program step by step. Selected as role model mentoring project managers in 3 project offices transferring to new way of project management.
- > Successfully managed over 18 projects/programs end to end for different operators in China, Tai Wan, Hong Kong, Japan and Singapore including creating SOW, planning, scoping, costing, controlling, managing changes, risks, stakeholders, supplier/subcontractor etc.
- > Contract value ranged up to 10M USD. Solution areas involved network rollout, business and operation consulting, system integration, software development of different scales.
  - **Projects & Achievements:** Hong Kong SmarTone VoLTE (Voice over LTE i.e. 4G) Project. Served as program director to negotiate scope, beat competitors, secure contract finally. Led a cross-functional onsite team of over 40 members to realize and deploy this complex solution integrating with 2G/3G/4G. Ericsson first commercial launched VoLTE in this region. Achieved 15% margin improved, shared as best practice and contributed to Ericsson's VoLTE blueprint. Developed AP/GW solution (AIS, Linux, Oracle, MySQL, C/C++, JAVA, Tomcat, struts2, Mina) which have been reused by 4 different markets. Helped SmarTone become one of the first authorized Iphone6 operators around world. Check out another 15 projects

## Team Lead, Crossbow Technology Inc. 2006—2007

- > Drove firmware development and migration among different hardware platforms for machine to machine solution to meet different customer requirements.
- Coordinated software and hardware team customizing solution for mine and land monitoring. **Projects & Achievements:** Platform Migration, Auto-Testing System, Land Monitoring

### Technical Project Manager, Lucent Technology Inc. 1998-2001

- > Started as an engineer deploying 5ESS (#5 Electronic Switch System) and gained technical reputation very soon, then led projects technical troubleshooting and contractor training.
- > Successfully delivered very large scale network rollout in 3 different big cities as a technical project manager in charge of planning, logistics, installation, acceptance and handover etc.

Projects & Achievements: PHS rollout, One Tel Australia MSC, and Network Migration

Barry Wang Page 2 of 3

#### **Awards**

- > Excellent Employee of Ericsson North East Asia in 2009 and 2012
- > Excellent Team Award CNC Integrated Service Platform 1.0 Phase 2 Rollout in 2008
- > Excellent Employee of Lucent Tsing Dao in 1999 and 2000

## **Trainings**

- Leadership for Professionals / Leadership for Project Managers
- SI Campus/Enjoy Customer Service
- > Way to Ericsson Agile leader/ Way to Ericsson Coacher/ Kan Ban/This is Lean
- > AWS Business Professional/AWS technical Professional/Making Great Hiring Decisions

#### **Education**

- ➤ 2003–2006 Institute of Software, Chinese Academy of Science Master in Computer Networks and Multimedia Communication
- > 1994–1998 Ocean University of China Bachelor of Computer Software (Minored in Law)

Barry Wang Page 3 of 3